Brianna Hinds

briden32016@gmail.com | (210)-288-7673 | Houston, TX

www.linkedin.com/in/brianna-hinds

SUMMARY

Highly motivated computer science student with 4 years of programming experience in various languages and a passion for software development with a keen interest in artificial intelligence, machine learning, and data analytics. Eager to apply academic knowledge, problem solving skills and practical experience to contribute to innovative projects and grow as a programmer. Also, a dedicated D1 track and field athlete, demonstrating adaptiveness, discipline, determination, and teamwork.

EDUCATION

Houston Christian University

Houston, Texas

Extracurriculars: Part of the HCU Track Team, President of Robotics and Engineering Organization (REO)

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Database Management Systems, Operating Systems

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Science Researcher | Employer: Purdue University | West Lafayette, IN, Remote | August 2024 - Present

- Collaborating with Houston Fire Department on analyzing their station data to improve HFD performance.
- Developing data-driven strategies to optimize resource allocation and response times.
- Applying Python and R, I am implementing data science cleaning, processing, and visualization tools to present the results of the analysis.

Machine Learning Research Assistant | Employer: Houston Christian University | Houston, TX | May 2024 - Present

- Applying my knowledge in PyTorch and data analysis, I built a Graph Convolution Networks(GCN) to aid in the prediction of cancers types based on gene expressions. Visualizations such as tSNE were implemented to show the relationship of the data.
- Fine tuned GCN's using Bayesian Optimization to find a classification model architecture of 96% accuracy.
- Built a GCN to determine the Time-to-Event analysis of Ovarian Cancer patients, predicting when and if death will occur.

Computing Help Desk | Employer: Houston Christian University | Houston, TX | August 2023 - Present

- Applying my knowledge of computer science concepts to help students with homework, projects, and test prep.
- Troubleshooting and debugging any issues students have with their Python, Java, or SOL programs.

PROJECTS

NASAMINDS: AI Inventory Tracking | Team Project in collaboration with NASA | Python, PyTorch | January-March 2024

- Built, trained, and tested an Artificial Neural Network to localize an object on an x-y plane based on RFID data (signals and frequency).
- Model concluded with very low error and our mapping visualization showed the ANN model's accuracy for predicting where an item was.

Sky-50 | Team Project | Python, DJI Tello Drone | March-May 2023

- Developed a license plate detection system that implemented a GUI to control the drone with a connected computer keyboard.
- User can operate takeoff, landing, and the drone's camera; where it can take a picture and record the license plate.
- Uses image recognition to read the license plate number and store it into a text file.
- Received an "Innovation Award" for demonstrating exceptional creativity and originality in its concepts and design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Familiar with Coding Languages: Python, SQL, R, Git, Java, Arduino/C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C
- Relevant Knowledge: OOP (Object-Oriented Programming), Machine Learning Models, Neural Networks, PyTorch, Figma
- Skills: Time Management, Communication Skills, Teamwork, Leadership, Microsoft Excel